Ruth Krauss Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Ruth Krauss Papers.
undated, 1929-1992.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Krauss, Ruth.
Johnson, Crockett, 1906-1975.
40.25 linear feet.
The Ruth Krauss Papers contain documents and artwork created by Ruth Krauss in her work as a children's author and poet. The collection also includes materials related to the publication of Krauss's books, such as galleys, illustrations, brochures, posters, and audio-visual materials. The collection contains some documents and artwork created by David Leisk (Crockett Johnson), Krauss's husband. Separated materials include monographs, serials, and audio-visual materials.
MSS19940007
Biographical Note
Ruth Krauss was born in 1901 in Baltimore, Maryland. She attended several universities and institutes. She received her bachelor's degree from the Parsons School of Fine and Applied Arts. In 1940, she married David Leisk (known as Crockett Johnson). From 1944 until 1979, Krauss published many children's works, some of which she illustrated herself. Other children's books were collaborations with her husband, usually employing Krauss's text and Johnson's illustrations. Krauss's career as a writer of adult poetry began in the late 1950s, with publications spanning 1965-1977. Many of these adult poems were experimental theatrical poems, many of which were performed in New York, New Haven, and Boston. Krauss died in 1993.
Scope and Contents
The Ruth Krauss Papers date from approximately 1938 through the early 1990s and include materials pertaining to Krauss's writing for children and for adults, from the earliest stages to final, published works. The collection also includes correspondence and financial records, and some material related to the work of Krauss's husband David Leisk (Crockett Johnson). Most materials date from the 1950s and 1960s.
The collection, especially in the Children's Literature series, is incomplete; the papers contain little or no materials pertaining to some of Krauss's works, especially some of the earlier ones.
Arrangement
The collection was received in considerable disarray. Related materials were not packaged together, and unrelated materials were often intermixed in large-size envelopes and folders. These envelopes and folders were occasionally mislabeled, but sometimes provide the only clues about the items' identity and date. Where these envelopes and folders were too worn, fragile, or acidic to be preserved, they have been photocopied.
Materials were subsequently sorted by type into series, and subdivided by title and/or date for ease of research. The collection often contained multiple photocopies of the same original; only one of these copies was retained.
Series I: Correspondence ( undated, 1947-1991 )
Series II: Children's Literature ( undated, 1947-1989 )
Series III: Prose ( undated, ca. 1938-1979 )
Series IV: Notebooks ( undated, 1954-1964 )
Series V: Crockett Johnson Materials ( undated, 1952-1986 )
Series VI: Manuscripts Submitted for Review ( undated, 1946-1989 )
Series VII: Financial and Other Records ( 1967-1990 )
Series VIII: Poetry ( undated, 1958-1988 )
Series IX: Artifacts ( undated, 1929-1992 )
Series X: Photographs ( undated, 1962-1982 )
Related Material
The Archives & Special Collections maintains many collections on children's literature and the publishing industry. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
Books, monographs, newspapers, newsletters, and serial publications have been separated and cataloged.
Books by Krauss
Backward Day (Dodd CLC C1363).
Bears (Dodd WPZ 338 and CLC C3441).
Big and Little (Dodd CLC C3442).
The Big World and the Little House (Dodd CLC C1364).
The Birthday Party (Dodd CLC A2309).
A Bouquet of Littles (Dodd CLC A2040).
The Cantilever Rainbow (Dodd CLC A2041, CLC A2042, CLC C1272).
The Carrot Seed (Dodd B3046; HBL PZ7 .K875 Car).
The Carrot Seed [large format] (Dodd MC 3 27)
Charlotte and the White Horse (Dodd CLC A2043).
Es Ist Fein Klein Zu Sein (Dodd CLC A2045).
German version of Open House for Butterflies.
Everything Under a Mushroom (Dodd CLC B148, WPZ 122).
The Great Duffy.
The Growing Story.
The Happy Day (Dodd CLC D422).
The Happy Egg.
"Himself" [postcards].
A Hole is to Dig (Dodd CLC A114, HBL PZ7.K875 Ho).
How to Make an Earthquake.
I Can Fly (Dodd CLC A1037).
I Want to Paint My Bathroom Blue.
I Write It.
If Only (Dodd WPS 2553).
I'll Be You and You Be Me (Dodd C3331).
Ik Kan Vliegen.
Imagine That!.
Is This You? (co-authored with Crockett Johnson).
Jar Vasicek Nerostl.
Jorden er Til at Sta Pa.
Little Boat Lighter than a Cork (Dodd A3164).
Little King, Little Queen, Little Monster.
Ein Loch Ist Was Man Grabt (Dodd CLC A2044).
German version of A Hole Is to Dig
Mama, I Wish I Was Snow.
Mina Olisin Sina ja Sina Olisit Mina.
Minestrone.
Monkey Day (Dodd XA I.2 no.26, CLC D36).
A Moon or a Button.
Open House for Butterflies.
Somebody Else's Nut Tree (Dodd CLC C839, C1333 copy 1 and copy 2).
Somebody Spilled the Sky.
There's a Little Ambiguity Over There Among the Bluebells (Dodd B3902, B3822, HBL oversize PS3561.R3 T5).
This Breast Gothic (Dodd WPS 1237).
Under 13 (Dodd WPS 1236).
Under Twenty (Dodd WPS 1235).
A Very Special House (Dodd CLC C719).
Viele viele Kinderspiele.
Books by Crockett Johnson
Aluo di tong hua guo (Dodd CLC A2095, copies 1 and 2).
Harold's Fairy Tale in Chinese.
Aluo you zhi cai ce bi (Dodd CLC A2089, copies 1 and 2).
Harold and the Purple Crayon in Chinese.
Barkis.
Barnaby (HBL Art Library NC 1429 L429 B37).
Barnaby 2: Mr. O'Malley and the Haunted House.
Barnaby 3: Jackeen J. O'Malley for Congress.
Barnaby 4: Mr. O'Malley Goes for the Gold.
Barnaby 6: J.J. O'Malley Goes to Hollywood.
Barnaby and Mr. O'Malley.
Blue Ribbon Puppies.
Castles in the Sand.
Ellen's Lion.
Emperor's Gift.
Frowning Prince (Dodd B3404).
Gordy and the Pirate.
Harold and the Purple Crayon (Dodd CLC A2073, CLC A2078, CLC A2079, CLC A2087, CLC A2074, CLC A2075, CLC A2076, CLC A2077, HBL PZ 7 L537 Har).
Harold and the Purple Crayon (in Hebrew).
Harold at the North Pole (Dodd CLC A2090).
Harold's ABC (Dodd CLC A2092, CLC A2091).
Harold's Circus (Dodd CLC A2204).
Harold's Fairy Tale (Dodd CLC A2096, CLC A2204).
Harold's Trip to the Sky (Dodd CLC A2097, CLC A2098, CLC A2099).
Ich Mach Mir Meine Eigne Welt (Dodd CLC A2086).
Harold and the Purple Crayon in German.
The Lion's Own Story (Dodd CLC B549).
The Little Fish that Got Away.
Merry Go Round and Round and Round.
Mickey's Magnet (Dodd CLC A1163).
Paultje en het Paarse Krijtje (Dodd CLC A2080).
Harold and the Purple Crayon in Dutch.
Paultje op Mars (Dodd CLC 2100).
Harold's Trip to the Sky in Dutch.
Pelle och den Roda Kritan (Dodd CLC A2088).
Harold and the Purple Crayon in Swedish.
Pelles aventyr (Dodd CLC A2094).
Harold's Fairy Tale in Swedish.
A Picture for Harold's Room (Dodd CLC A2101, CLC A2104, CLC A2102, CLC A2103).
The Saga of Quilby.
Terrible Terrifying Toby.
Time for Spring.
We Wonder What Will Walter Be, When He Grows Up? (Dodd CLC C170).
Who's Upside Down?
Will Spring Be Early? or Will Spring Be Late?.
Books, Broadsides, and Monographs by Others
Aldridge, Adele, Notpoems(1972) (Greater Hartford Library PS3551.L343 N6).
Anderson, David, Under Western Eyes (1970) (Dodd XA I.1 no.93).
Ansen, Alan, Disorderly Houses (1961) (Dodd A6757).
Ansen, Alan, The Old Religion (1959) (Dodd WPS 772).
Ashberry, John, April Galleons, (1987) (Dodd C4218, HBL PS3501.S475 A86 1987).
Ashberry, John, Rivers and Mountains (1966) (Dodd B2801, HBL 811.54 As32r).
At the Gallery (1972).
Auden, W.H., Making, Knowing, and Judging (1956) (HBL 808.1 Au23).
Baudelaire, Charles, Twenty Prose Poems (1968) (Dodd A6644).
Baxter, Glen, Drawings (1974) (Dodd XA I.2 no.87).
Beck, Regina, Looking at the Sun (1974).
Berkson, Bill, Recent Visitors (1973) (Dodd XA I.2 no.17, D1015).
Berkson, Bill, Shining Leaves (1969) (Dodd C2147).
Berkson, Bill, and Frank O'Hara, Hymns of St. Bridget (1974) (Dodd XA I.2 no.18).
Berrigan, Sandy, Daily Rites (1974) (Dodd WPS 3009).
Berrigan, Ted, The Drunken Boat (1974) (Dodd C2492).
Berrigan, Ted, and Anne Waldman, Memorial Day (1971) (Dodd XA I.4 no.93).
Bloedow, Jerry, Power (1977)
Bly, Robert, Sleepers Joining Hands (1973) (Dodd C4663/A6727).
Bly, Robert, The Teeth Mother Naked at Last (1970) (Dodd WPS 364).
Brainard, Joe, I Remember More (1972) (Dodd C2406).
Brainard, Joe, Some Drawings of Notes to Myself (1971) (Dodd C2211).
Breton, Andre, Fata Morgana (1969) (Dodd WPQ 47).
Broughton, John, Look In, Look Out (1968) (Dodd C1039).
Brown, Bob, 1450-1950 (1959) (Dodd B2243).
Brown, Rebecca, 3 Way Split (1978) (Dodd WPS 1390).
Brown, Rebecca, The Bicycle Trip and Poems (1974) (Dodd XA I.9 no 26).
Brown, Rebecca, Mouse Works (1971) (Dodd XA I.2 no. 55).
Brownstein, Michael, Highway to the Sky (1969) (Dodd B3139, HBL PS3552.R79 H5).
Bukowski, Charles, It Catches My Heart in Its Hands (1963) (Dodd C775).
Burndy Library, Heralds of Science (1955) (HBL Ref Z 7405 H6 B8 1969).
Burroughs, William, and Allen Ginsberg, The Yage Letters (1963) (HBL PS3552.U75 Y3, PS3552.U75 Y3 1988, PS3552.U75 Y3 1990).
Carey, Henry, Chrononhotonthologos (1971) (Dodd XA I.8 no.24)
Carroll, Jim, 4 Ups and 1 Down (1970) (Dodd XA I.3 no.38)
Cataldo, Susan, Brooklyn-Queens Day (1982) (Dodd XA I.9 no. 21).
Cavellini, Gugliemo Achille, Cimeli (1974).
Cavellini, Gugliemo Achille, Continuo La Serie delle Mie Mostre a Domicilio (1975)
Cendras, Blaise, Kodak (1976) (Dodd XA I.6 no. 134).
Ceravolo, Joseph, Fits of Dawn (1965) (Dodd C2204).
Clark, Tom, Car Wash (1970) (Dodd C2212).
Collom, Jack, Workday (1971) (Dodd XA I.7 no. 21).
Colony, Horatio, The Early Land (1962) (Dodd A6725).
Coolidge, Clark, The So: Poems 1966 (1966) (Dodd XA I.3 no. 65).
Cumberland, David, Death and Justice Frescoes (1971) (Dodd C3455, HBL PS3553.U43 D4).
Dawson, Fielding, The Girl with the Pale Cerulean Eyes: The Man with the Grey Hair (1974) (Dodd C2770).
Deitch, Gene, The Picture Book Animated (1978).
Demise, Phil, What I Don't Know for Sure (1978).
Dibner, Bern, Luigi Galvani (1979).
Di Palma, Raymond, Borgia Circles (1972)
Di Prima, Diana, Dinners and Nightmares (1961) (Dodd B4412, HBL PS3507.I68 D56 1998).
Donnelly, Dorothy, Kudzu and Other Poems (1978) (Dodd A6645).
Duncan, Robert, Selected Poems (1959) (Dodd WPS 274).
Eaton, Charles Edward, Countermoves (1962) (Dodd A6756).
Edson, Russell, The Boundary (1964) (WPS 1813).
Edson, Russell, A Stone is Nobody's: Fables & Drawings (1961) (WPS 1634).
Elmslie, Kenward, City Juncket (1972) (Dodd A3866, C2074).
Elmslie, Kenward, Communications Equipment (1979) (Dodd WPS 1576).
Fagin, Larry, Brain Damage (1970) (Dodd C2155)
Fagin, Larry, Landscape (1972) (Dodd WPS 528).
Fagin, Larry, Twelve Poems (1972) (Dodd WPS 527).
Famous Authors and Artists, Volume 2.
Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, Starting from San Francisco (1961) (Dodd B2486, HBL PS3511.E557 S8 1967, Greater Hartford PS3511.E557 S8, Stamford PS3511.E557 S8)
Ferrari, Mary, The Flying Glove (Dodd XA I.1 no.108)
Fessenden, Anne, Around Some Corner (1966).
Finaly, Ian Hamilton, 4 Sails (1966) (Dodd WPR 578).
Finaly, Ian Hamilton, 5 Poems (Dodd WPR 743).
Finaly, Ian Hamilton, 6 Songs (Dodd WPR 144).
Finlay, Ian Hamilton, Autumn Poem (1966) (Dodd WPR 147).
Finlay, Ian Hamilton, Canal Stripe Series 4 (1964) (Dodd XA I 4 no 158).
Finlay, Ian Hamilton, Cytheria (1965)(Dodd XA I.1 no 38).
Finlay, Ian Hamilton, Futura
Finlay, Ian Hamilton, How Blue! (1965) (Dodd XA I.4 no. 156).
Finlay, Ian Hamilton. I lo lov love (Dodd WPR744).
Freeman, Mae, and Ira Freeman, Fun with Chemistry (1982)
Frasconi, Antonio, "A Calendar for 1960" (1960).
Freilicher, Melvyn, History Lessons (Ancient).
Freilicher, Melvyn, History Lessons: etc. Post Post Post Post-Post Post Modernism, The Past.
Freilicher, Melvyn, The Meaning of the Word "Inspriation": My Autobiography.
Freilicher, Melvyn, Genre Studies: The Novel.
Freilicher, Melvyn, Genre Studies: The Textbook.
Freilicher, Melvyn, The Necessity of Art and the Necessity of (Radical) Politics in Revolutionary Struggle (1973).
Gag, Wanda, Millions of Cats [filmstrip text].
Galwey, G.V., Babel: A Play with Music for Youth Theater
Garcia Lorca, Federico, Divan & Other Writings (1974) (Dodd A6726).
Ginsberg, Allan, Empty Mirror (1961) (Dodd WPS 1045).
Ginsberg, Allan, Planet News (1968) (Dodd A1764, HBL PS3513.I74 P6 1968).
Giorno, John, Birds (1971) (Dodd C2409)
Giorno, John, Cum (1971) (Dodd C2405)
Gizzi, Michael, Species of Intoxication (1983).
Gjelsness, Barent, On the Raft (1970).
Godfrey, John, Twenty-Six Poems (1971) (Dodd XA I.1 no. 44).
Goscinny, Les Lauriers de Cesar (1972) (Dodd CLC D19).
Graphic Art of Hnizdovsky (1977).
Gray, Darrell, and Allan Kornblum,Good Morning (1975).
Greenwald, Ted, Makes Sense (1975) (Dodd XA I.1 no. 115).
Greenwald, Ted, Making a Living (1973) (Dodd XA I.8 no. 23).
Gross, Ronald, "Variations on a Line by Ruth Krauss" [broadside] (1968).
Haber, Ira Joel, Radio City Music Hall (1969)
Hamill, Janet, The Temple (1980) (Dodd WPS 3011).
Harms, Valerie, ed. Convocation! Women in Writing (1975) (Dodd A6646).
Harriman, John, Taxi (1969).
Hartman, Yuki, Hot Footsteps (1976) (Dodd WPS 1343).
Harwood, Lee, The Man with the Blue Eyes (1966) (Dodd WPR 163).
Hausman, Gerald, "El Porvenir" (no date).
Hausman, Gerald, New Marlboro Stage (1969) (Dodd A3903, A3904)
Hejinian, Lyn, A Mask of Motion (1977) (Dodd WPS 1912, HBL PS3558.E4735 M3).
Howe, Fanny, Alsace-Lorraine (1982) (Dodd XA I.9 no. 23).
Howe, Fanny, The Amerindian Coastline Poem (1975) (Dodd WPS 1206).
Howe, Susan, Hinge Picture (1974) (Dodd XA I.7 no. 18).
Ironbiter, Suzanne, Devi (1983).
James, Jimmy D., Phoenix Unbound (1982).
Klappert, Peter, ed., A Small Anthology of Contemporary American Poetry (no date).
Klappert, Peter, After the Rhymers' Guild (1972).
Koch, Kenneth, Days and Nights (1982) (Dodd B3616, HBL PS3521.O27 D3 1982).
Kostelanetz, Richard, et al., Fifth Assembling (1974).
Kostelanetz, Richard, and Henry Korn, eds., Seventh Assembling (no date).
Krafft, Charles, "Tomorrow is a Great Hit Wherever Shown" (1968).
Krauss, Janet, The Unpinned Eyes (1972?).
Kwock, C.H., and Victor McHugh, Why I Live on the Mountain: 30 Chinese Poems from the Great Dynasties (1958).
Laforgue, Jules, Quelques poèmes (1973) (Dodd F409).
Lance, Lawrence, Cruelty (Dodd WPS 3698).
Leon, More Pictures of Leon (1970) (Dodd XA I.8 no. 125).
Malmude, Steve, Catting (1972) (Dodd XA I.1 no. 113).
Marathon (radio program transcript, May 1970).
Matthews, Harry, Trial Impressions (1977).
Metcalf, Paul, Will West (1973) (Dodd B2250, B2491).
Metras, Gary, Destiny's Calendar (no date).
Miller, Casey, and Kate Swift, Handbook of Nonsexist Writing (1980) (Dodd A6647).
Miller, Dorothy C., ed., Americans 1963 (1963) (HBL Art Library N6512 .N416).
Moonseed (1972) (Dodd A6648).
Morice, Dave, Tilt (no date).
Morrisette, Bruce, Alain Robbe-Grillet (1965) (HBL 809.092 C723 no.11).
Murphy, Romaine, and Lynne Savitt, Gravida: Heavy with Child (1973).
Nations, Opal, A Pen, Some Paper, Pen & Paper (1976).
Neely, Henry M., The Star Finder
Nelson, Nels C., South African Rock Pictures (1937) (Dodd Olsen f66).
New School Poets (no date).
North, Charles, Elizabethan and Nova Scotian Music (1974).
O'Hara, Frank, Lunch Poems (1964) (Dodd WPS 752, HBL and Torrington PS3529.H28 L8).
O'Hara, Frank, Meditations in an Emergency (1959) (Dodd B3030, Olsen 286).
O'Hara, Frank, Nakian (1966) (Dodd C2779, HBL Art Library NB237.N4 A53).
O'Hara, Frank, Odes (1969) (Dodd F328, WPS 758).
O'Hara, Frank, Second Avenue (1960) (Dodd WPS 378, HBL 811.54 Oh1s).
Oldenburg, Patti, Poems Travelling (1973) (Dodd C2785).
Oppenheimer, Joel, The Love Bit (1962) (Dodd WPS 3084, HBL 811.54 Op51l).
Overleaf: A Collection of Short Stories (1973) (Dodd C5001).
Owen, Maureen, Country Rush (1973).
Owen, Maureen, Hearts in Space (1980) (Dodd C1606).
Padgett, Ron, Tulsa Kid (1979) (Dodd C4022, C4023).
Padgett, Ron, and Joel Brainard, Sufferin' Succotash (1971) (Dodd C2411).
Palmer, Doug, The Quick and the Quiet (1965) (Dodd XA I.1 no. 49).
Parra, Nicanor, Anti-poems (1960) (Dodd WPQ 26).
Paz, Octavio, [Rukeyser, Muriel, trans.], Sun Stone (1963)(HBL 861.64 P298p YR).
Peters, Robert L., and George Hitchcock, Pioneers of Modern Poetry (1967) (Dodd WPS 2224, HBL PN6101 .P4)
Pommy-Vega, Janine, Morning Passage (1976) (Dodd WPS 3007, HBL PS3566.O58 M6).
Presson, Bill, Before Next (1971).
Rannit, Aleksis, Heiti Talvik, an Estonian Poet (1904-47): From Decadent Dream to Martyrdom. (1976).
Reti, Ladislao, and Bern Dibner, Leonardo da Vinci, Technologist (1969).
Rilke, Rainer Maria, The Duino Elegies (1972) (Dodd A6649).
Rolfe, Edwin, Permit Me Refuge (1955) (Dodd B2986).
Rorum, Ned, Four Dialogues for Two Voices and Two Pianos (1969) (Dodd XA II.2 no. 3)
Rosenburg, David, Blues of the Sky (1974) (Dodd B3169, HBL BS1440.A1 R67 1976).
San Diego Bobcats, My Travels with Mae: A Joint Experience (1977).
Sanders, Ed, Peace Eye (1965) (Dodd C884, Olsen 977a, Olsen 977b, Olsen 978).
Sanders, Ed, Poem from Jail (1963) (Dodd WPS 361, Olsen 979).
Schuyler, James, A Sun Cab (1972) (Dodd XA I.6 no.99).
Seeing, Feeling, Thinking (no date).
Seferis, George, [Warner, Rex, trans.], Poems (1960) (Dodd A6650).
Selz, Peter, The Work of Jean Debuffet (1962) (HBL Art and Greater Hartford ND553.D772 S4).
Shariati, Ali, [Ghassemy, Ali Asghar, trans.], One Followed by an Eternity of Zeroes (1979).
Shariati, Ali, [Ghassemy, Ali Asghar, trans.],Selection and / or Election (1979).
Sherman, Susan, Areas of Silence (1963).
Snyder, Gary, Earth House Hold (1969) (Dodd B1287, HBL PS3537.N79 E2).
Speigelman, Art, and Bob Schneider, Whole Grains: A Book of Quotations (1973).
Spicer, Jack, Admonitions (1974) (Dodd C2467).
Stanton, Johnny, Slip of the Tongue (1969) (Dodd XA I.1 no. 101).
Steele, Benjamin, and Charles Parriot, Ginseng: Twenty Poems (no date).
Stokes, Terry, "For Jim, Again" (1978).
Struther, Jan, Mrs. Miniver (1943) (HBL 823.91 St8).
Thomas, Bill, ed., Things: Writings by Children (1968).
Thomas, Bill, Straighthru (1970).
Thomas, Bill, The Forest (no date).
Thomas, Dylan, A Child's Christmas in Wales (1954, 1959)(Dodd A2176, HBL DA730 .T44 1959)
Tonto Lavoris (1972) (Dodd XA I.8 no.27).
Torregian, Sotere, Amtrak Trek: Being Poems and Prose Written Cross-Country from California to New York (1979) (Dodd WPS 1478).
Transtromer, Tomas, [Bly, Robert, trans.], Truth Barriers (1961).
Tuesday Night Workshop, Phil, Honey, It's Time We Settled Down (1982).
2 Unidentified Hebrew books.
Untitled poetry anthology.
Veitch, Tom, and Clark Coolidge, To Obtain the Value of the Cake Measure from Zero (1970) (Dodd XA I.6 no. 133).
Veitch, Tom, Death College (1970) (Dodd XA I.3 no. 4).
Violi, Paul, She'll Be Riding Six White Horses (1970).
Violi, Paul, Some Poems (1976) (Dodd WPS 1447).
Vostell, Volf, Television Decollage and Morning Glory (1963).
Wagner, Charles A., ed., Prize Poems 1913-29 (1930) (Dodd A6651).
Wakowski, Diane, Dream Sheet (1965) (Dodd X I.2 no. 42).
Waldman, Anne, First Baby Poems (1983) (Dodd B3764, WPS 1703).
Waldman, Anne, "The Holy City" (1971), (Dodd XA I.1 no. 203).
Waldman, Anne, "Light and Shadow" (1972) (Dodd XA I.7 no.12).
Waldman, Anne, "Up through the Years" (1971) (Dodd XA I.7 no. 67, XA I.1 no. 67).
Waldman, Anne, "West Indies Poems" (1972) (Dodd XA I.1 no.69).
Waldman, Anne, ed., The World Anthology (1969) (Dodd B5048, HBL PS615 .W3).
Waldrop, Keith, The Space of a Half an Hour (1983) (Dodd C3503).
Warsh, Lewis, The Suicide Rates (1967) (Dodd WPS 830).
Warsh, Lewis, Today (1974) (Dodd XA I.1 no. 58).
Weigel, Tom, Twenty-four Haiku after the Japanese (1982) (Dodd C4953).
Weingarten, Don, Lord Scum's Hotel (1971) (Dodd XA I.1 no. 104).
Wesleyan Poets (no date).
Wieners, John, Ace of Pentacles (1964) (Dodd C380, C5548, Olsen 1154).
Wieners, John, The Hotel Wentley Poems (1958) (Dodd WPS 590 c. 1 and c.2, HBL 811.54 W636h).
Wilkie, Britton, "I Walk into Doors" (no date) (Dodd XA II.1 no. 71).
Wiliams, C.K., The Lark. The Thrush. The Starling. (1983) (Dodd WPS 2781).
Wilson, Jill, Beside Any Ocean (1974).
Winks, Jeffrey, Flowers Grow from Your Dirt (1972).
Wright, Rebecca, Ciao, Manhattan (1977) (Dodd WPS 3008, HBL PS3573.R5377 C5).
Wright, Rebecca, Elusive Continent (1972)
Young, Ian, ed., The Male Muse (1973) (Dodd B3286).
Periodicals
Adventures in Poetry, 1, 6 (June 1970), 7 (Feb. 1971), 9 (Spring 1972), 11
Advocate Extra, 15 June, 1984.
American Book Review, 2:6, 7:1, Nov/Dec. 1981, Summer 1979, Oct. 1979, Nov/Dec. 1983
American PEN, 5:4, 6:1-3, 7:4.
American PENewsletter, 16, 26, 28, 30, 31, 36.
American Poetry Review 4:1, 4:4, 10:6, 12:4, 12:6, 13:1-3, 14:1-3, 15:1, 15:3
Angel Hair, 2, 5, 6.
Art and Literature, 9.
Art News, Summer 1967.
Artspeak, 9:2-8.
Asparagus, 3:38-39, 6/1984.
Aspen Magazine, 8.
Atlantic, August 1965
Authors Guild Bulletin, April 1961, Oct./Nov. 1968, July-Sept. 1969, Oct./Nov. 1969, May/June 1971, Oct./Nov. 1971, Jan. 1972, Sept./Oct. 1976, Dec. 1976/Jan. 1977, June-Aug. 1977, April-June 1978, Oct./Nov. 1978, Sept./Oct. 1979, May/June 1980, Winter 1982-83, Spring 1984, Summer 1984, Fall 1984, Winter 1985-86.
Bard's Bugle, 1:2, 1:4.
Berkshire Magazine, Summer 1974.
Better Nutrition, 7/1986.
Big Sky, 5 (1973), 11/12.
Big Table, 1-5.
Blue Pig, 11, 14, 16
Bondage and Discipline, Special Prototype Issue (Dodd WPS 3697).
Book Week, 1 Nov., 1964.
Boston Eagle, 3 (Nov. 1974).
Bread and Puppet Newspaper, 5-6.
Brown Sweater, 1.
Brown Sweater Free Poems, 2.
Bulletin Second Front, March-May, 1976, Winter 1984
C: A Journal of Poetry, 1:4-10, 7.
Caterpillar, 5.
Civil Liberties, 362.
Coda, 1:1-2:2, 2:6-7, 3:2-5, 4:2, 4:5, 5:1, 5:3-5, 6:1, 6:5, 7:2, 8:1, 9:3-4, 10:1-2, 10:5, 11:1-3, 11:5, 12:1-3, 12:5, 13:3-4, Supplement,
Colony News, 17:1.
Colophon, 3-4.
Confrontation, Summer, 1982.
Connecticut River Review, 7:2.
Connecticut Traveller, 4:6.
Convene, 1989.
El Corno Emplumado, 3.
Cricket, 1:1.
Cross-Country, 10-11.
Cross-Cultural Review, 7.
Dispatch, 1:5-6, 1:8,
Dimension, 5:1 (1972)
Do It NOW!, 9:4.
Downhere, 1.
East Village Other, 2:2.
Elementary English, 37:2.
Evergreen Review, 28 (Jan.-Feb. 1973.
Exquisite Corpse, 2:1, 3:11-12.
Fairpress, 11 Sept. 1985.
Film Comment, 1:3.
Filmwise, 2.
Fits, 1-2.
Floating Bear, 1-21, 23, 25-29, 31, 35-37.
General Schmuck, 5.
Greenpeace Action, no date.
Gum, 6-8.
Hardware is Software
Hardware Poets Occasional, 1:1, 2, 4, 5, 7, 8.
Hasty Papers, 1960.
Hay Day Rural Times, 7:3-4.
Head, 4.
Herald Tribune Book Review, 9 Oct. 1960.
Herald's Magazine, 15 Dec. 1957.
How(ever), 1:2-3.
Human Behavior, May 1977.
IKON, 1:4-5, 6-7
Illuminations, 11.
Image, 2:6 Winter/Spring 1966, 14 Dec. 1986.
Jargon, 31.
Kauri, 7-10, 12 (Jan/Feb, 1966), 17, 21, 24, 27-28.
Kayak, 1.
Kulchur, 13, 18.
La Bas, 1-5, 7, 9-10.
Learn Something America, 2.
Linus, 1:5 (Aug. 1965.)
Lithopinion, 10:2.
Locus Solus, 2. (A1364)
Manhattan Arts, 4:4.
Margins, 16, 18-19, 27-30.
Mark, Oct. 17. 1954,
Nadada, 1.
Nation, 30 June 1962.
National Forum, Fall 1980.
National NOW Times, 11:7.
Neurotica, 9.
New Criterion, 2:6, 2:10
New Letters, 42:1 (Fall 1975)
New York Review of Books, 14:7, 14:10, 21:10, 30:11, 30:19, 2 May 1976.
New York Times Book Review, Feb. 1970, 24 Sept. 1989.
New Yorker, 28 Nov. 1953, 23 Jan. 1954, 9 Nov. 1968, 1 Nov. 1969, 3 Oct. 1970.
News and Reviews, Nov. 1985.
NewstART, 6.
Nitty-Gritty, 1:1.
Northwood Journal, 4:8.
Nuclear Times, 2:8.
Only Prose, Oct. 1978.
Out of This World, Summer 1973.
Outsider, 4/5.
Parents' Choice, Sept./Oct. 1978, 14:3 (1990).
Partisan Review 3, 47:3 (1980)
Peace & Freedom, 43:5.
PEN American Center Newsletter, 41, 45, 52-53, 55, 60, 63.
Penumbra, 11.
Un Poco Loco, Oct. 1979.
Poesie USA, 1:4.
Poetry, 109:1, 115:1, 115:3.
Poetry Comics, 9-10, 15.
Poetry Northwest, 17:3.
Poetry Now, 1:4, 2:1, 6:2, 6:6